# callie gorman

# calliegorman.design linkedin.com/calliegorman

calliegorman4@gmail.com 201-638-4568

# **DESIGN SKILLS**

User Research

Competitive Analysis

**Usability Testing** 

Persona Creation

Sitemaps

User Stories/Flows

Sketching

Wireframing

Prototyping

Branding

Visual Design

#### **FRONTEND**

**HTML** 

CSS

Bootstrap

Javascript

jQuery

Github

## **TOOLS**

Sketch

Figma

Invision

myBalsamiq

Draw.io

Illustrator

InDesign

# callie gorman. Digital Marketer turned Designer

I am a UX Designer with 5+ years of experience marketing in the tech industry.

My education in psychology and past work as a digital marketer have given me an ability to conduct effective user research, and therefore allows me to create intuitive designs that can increase user engagement rates to meet business goals.

#### RECENT PROJECTS

Led the UX process, including design creation, competitive and user research, and usability testing for:

#### vicarious

view prototype | view case study

A mobile travel app that prompts users to provides brief updates on each day of travel for family and friends.

#### connected

view prototype | view case study

A cloud-based storage application that features an intuitive interface, collaboration options, and dashboard personalization.

# RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

# **Digital Strategist**

Jan 2015 - Dec 2017

IBM Analytics, NYC | Remote

- Implemented A/B tests to drive higher web engagement rates
- Worked closely with design and development teams to build web strategies for new products and marketing plays
- Led strategy for 10+ quarterly digital campaigns that contributed more than \$1M of yearly marketing created revenue

#### Digital Lead

Dec 2016 - May 2017

Tribeca Film Festival, NYC | Remote

Chosen to develop digital and social media strategy for IBM / Tribeca Film Festival partnership.

#### **Project Manager**

Jan 2015 - April 2016

IBM Outthink Tour, NYC | Remote

Selected as lead project manager on a premiere event series, managing 10 teammates for events that drove 2000 net new clients.

#### **LEADERSHIP**

#### **IBM Marketing Mentor**

Jan 2015 - May 2017

Chosen by managers to mentor five new employees during their onboarding.

# **EDUCATION**

#### UX/UI Design Program, Bloc

Dec 2017 - July 2018

Intensive user-centered design program building real web and mobile app designs.

## College of the Holy Cross

May 2012

BA, Psychology, Pre-Business